hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft
this is a little bit of a strange start
because you'll see that i'm wearing a
black and white striped shirt that's
because i just refereed
some wrestling hermitcraft wrestling and
it was super weird
but i actually got given at the end of
it lots and lots
of heads all of which were killed by pvp
in the arena now i don't see a reason
why i can't submit this
for the seven different pvp hermit heads
except actually i've only got six
so i may have to i may have to do
something a little bit cheesy
here we go eat it and this will bring it
up to seven
minecraft heads eat the arrow and one
more one
there we go this is
a huge huge bounty
so seven different pvp hermit heads
300 points boom boom
okay well that is that is a really good
start to the episode
let's head on back to the base because i
need to pick up some resources
for my new shop so we're gonna pick up
some logs because
i actually have an idea for what i would
like to do
for my shop oh and of course i have to
go and pick up the stock
which is over here how am i gonna
transport this much
to gravel to sand and head back to the
shopping district
you know what it's actually way more fun
to just uh wizard fruit there so
scar can i have some wizard fruit please
there we go all right i'll see you later
and there we go now where do i make
my shop now i did claim a little bit of
land here
but i've oh no wait my plan doesn't work
at all
this is oh it's all sinking around me
this doesn't work okay so i i have got
this little bit of space reserved
okay but here's the issue i brought
enough wood with me
to make a pretty decent sized boat i was
gonna make a shop that was a boat and it
would be
docked somewhere around the island and
it would just sell whatever i want
the issue with this is that i'm broke
like
mega broke i don't got a single diamond
not one i got some tools and stuff so
i'm gonna have to make
what was gonna be a massive [\h__\h] in this
tiny square and i won't even be able to
buy the land to make a dock see
that you know what we're gonna use this
space but we're gonna move it there's
nothing wrong with moving it
we'll unclaim this land and take it
somewhere else so let's just move it
really close for now because here's what
we're gonna do
we're gonna have to make something small
time
and then work our way up from the bottom
so whatever diamonds we make we will
reinvest
and get back into making a bigger better
shop
okay let's make sure we keep this within
the 10 block limit
man i just realized quite how few
diamonds we have
let's hope that this is successful okay
this is all with all the space that
we've got
it's gonna i don't even think i can fit
a boat in here
yeah it would be a pretty small boat
don't you think i don't even think it's
worth doing that okay we're gonna have
to improvise
if we're starting from the bottom we're
gonna start from the very bottom
since we have such little space
i think i'm gonna have to go for like a
little raft we can make it out of
campfires
and extinguish all of them now it's a
bit weird the campfire
obviously if i place it there it's not
very good raft if it's underwater but if
you place it here
it kind of floats on the water so that
also doesn't
really work so the compromise is that
it's sitting on top of a
spruce trap door and then have a little
jetty out to the end here
this is uh this is a little embarrassing
really this is this is an embarrassing
first shop i picked it up i was like
yeah i'm gonna make a big shot we're
gonna sell all the cool stuff
and then i'm making this tiny little
raft oh my goodness
what it lacks in grandness it will make
up for in
tiny little details official chris and
her the
hms ggg
which of course stands for great
green goodies this
is straight up a symbol of our wealth
this is how poor we are we got nothing
we got a small raft
please come here and buy some things i
just need a couple more items to
decorate this
and then unfortunately i'm gonna have to
call this done because
yeah i it's just a space thing but this
is humble beginnings everyone this is
what it looks like
this is the bottom and over the course
of this season
it probably wouldn't even take the full
season to be honest this is gonna
upgrade
the more diamonds we get the more we can
invest in some land
and the bigger this will grow let's go
back to the base and get those bits
and let's take a look i need some
flowers to
attract people there some pots to put
them in and lanterns and all those bits
that you never really carry around with
you
i think that should do it actually all
right let's look back
zup there we go another thing you can do
is use
leads on star on these fences to give
them a little extra detail but we need a
mob for that
and of course we're in the biome with
absolutely nothing
nothing i think the question we all want
to know the answer to is can you put a
lead on a fish
the answer is no unfortunately not
come on in you get any yet this is this
is
this would be so much easier if this was
a chicken there we go
in and then we right click that
oh no no no no no oh okay mistakes were
made
all right got a block on top of them
this time and then we put the lead
right there it doesn't look quite as
neat and tidy as i was hoping
but it'll do there we go that looks
quite good it looks like the rope is
actually tethered under water somewhere
that looks pretty cool i think you can
hear you can hear the
the mooing under there though i'm happy
with it welcome
to the hms ggg great green
goodies let's fill this thing up now the
next thing is how much do we charge i
think this
early stage and how broke we are one
diamond times two stacks
we got a few barrels of sand going on
here and
a full chest of gravel and we are done
with our first shop this is not what i
had in mind
to be honest with you but i think this
has lots of potential and we're finally
we finally got something on the market
so hopefully we get some sales
while we continue to work on the base
why am i flying we don't need to fly
anymore we can we can just step out of
here
boop i think that's my new favorite
trick even though it's not real magic
it's still my favorite trick i mean i
wonder what happens if you
if what happens if you fly really really
high
up in the air and then you use a magic
freak
well i'll tell you what other magic's
going on i vanishing and i
i think i'm being snapped yeah
mr scar i don't feel so good all right
let's see what happens
if you eat this mid-air whoa whoa
well okay just puts you back on the
ground
now that's interesting
very interesting that could be a
potentially
very good escape if someone's after you
you fly in the air
and then you just magic yourself back
down
oh it could end badly now that we got
the shop out of the way i want to
continue working on
my base you might be fooled into
thinking that this
is looking relatively finished actually
it's not it's not at all it's not even
50 done like i've got this face done
but actually it's not even half the size
that it's going to be because
you might notice i've got some blocks
tailored all the way
around the base well
there's a lot of terrain that's going to
happen but it doesn't just stop there i
actually need
to remove all of these blocks down here
so that that cliff is even bigger and
then when that cliff is in there there's
actually going to be more mansion that
comes out the side of it
so imagine this but another one
underneath
it's going to be it's going to go out a
bit further to the left and the right it
might even go a bit higher at the back i
don't know yet but it's
going to be enormous and it's going to
be amazing i really wanted to challenge
myself
this season with the diagonals and the
gradient building
but i'm actually going to change myself
so much more by making this about twice
as big as i originally intended
so wait what's this in my inventory
time lapse huh well i guess you know
what time it is
[Music]
it may have taken you 20 seconds to
watch that clip
but it took me six hours of this
yep i have had more than enough
of excavating this stuff but the great
news is
i've got so much
stone look at all this dirt stone grass
this will be
more than enough to one finish the build
two terrain around here you can see i've
like matched the shape
and my goodness have i realized one
idiot i've been
this took a long time and this isn't
even half
and look how bad it gets over here can
you imagine having to take out
all of this as well
oh i might have taken on a task
which was very unwise but since it is a
new day
on the hermitcraft server i'm going to
check out what new bounties there are
got to get them points actually while
we're here why don't we check if we've
had any sales i know it's only been like
a day
i owe you half a diamond oh
oh look at that 27
gravel gravel as well oh my goodness
only a day it only took a day 55
diamonds
55 diamonds we are gonna upgrade
today we are gonna i mean i only built
this yesterday but it's already gonna
get upgraded now
i need to be smart i can't spend all of
this on land straight away
maybe i can upgrade it a bit because i
owe i owe
i owe impulse so much money yeah look at
that now i'm going to take that iou back
because
i am going to pay for what i've already
do that doesn't leave a lot
so yeah no more iou i'm going to put
some diamonds in there oh man
paying off my debts now what i actually
came here for was this thing
the bounty board this is where the big
points are at let's have a look we got
beef
cod head again man what is with the cod
heads
great great grain pvp
who is this grain character and scar
green green and scar no way
and ren is scar online oh my goodness
scar
can you uh come to the uh
bounty board one second
we're gonna see if i can communicate
entirely
silently to scar and we'll see if he
understands let's put all our stuff in
here we'll set our spawn and now
we wait that chest monster is super
scary in the background
oh there is scar scar okay okay okay
okay
let's see if let's see if he can
understand look if i if i point
look look look look here here wrong one
look at this one
hmm come on now look look look
scott over here look i've i've respawned
okay now let's see if he can get it how
dare you scar i i can't
believe you would do that
unbelievable scott work it out
work it out come on do i have to do this
do i have to do this
no way i won't let you
get away with this
there we go he's got it
i'm nodding i'm nodding do more go go
[Music]
hey got it he got it now now he should
give me the sword
give me the sword i will get my
revenge scar
yes i think you've got it
[Laughter]
yes
and now now we now we just submit the
head
scar 150 points
okay got that out my system
let's be friends
oh my goodness if we just me and scott
we just keep nodding at each other
i believe my work here is done okay we
got three diamond blocks and we got
three extra diamonds
three whole diamonds man spent quite a
lot already
so we're gonna buy three more plots one
two three four
right there it's still not gonna be big
enough but we need to we need to expand
this
right away one two three didn't take
long but now i think what we should do
is actually make a bigger raft here
and then sell some more goods and then
upgrade it again we're probably going to
need
a well yeah a lot more land than i
currently have
and i'm already poor again i've marked
out how much more land i've got
and i've got to admit if i was going to
make a boat it probably well it would
have this sort of shape and it probably
wouldn't have enough space so
all i'm gonna do for now is upgrade this
barge of this raft to be
a bit bigger and then next time when we
get more diamonds
we can buy more land extend the water
and do better
i have all the necessary resources so we
can get going
at once it totally looks like i've just
set the entire raft on fire
well at least my shop is lit i want
these little platforms here so that i
can actually
stack things on top of it mixture of
trapdoors and signs
this is a very spruce heavy build there
we go
massive upgrade already it's way way
bigger
and i can store more barrels that make
more sense
people will find it a lot easier to shop
here now
and for good measure i can start selling
another one
which will be golden carrots all we need
to do now is fill this up with stock and
wait for some more diamonds to roll
in the question is how much do we charge
for these golden carrots
because there's actually someone already
selling carrots over there
let's check how much they charge one
diamond per stack
and they're making some sales so i'm
pretty sure we can double up on that
okay so
one diamond for two stacks all right we
are all stocked up there's sand
absolutely everywhere there's gravel
and the shop has been thoroughly
thoroughly upgraded
it was once a poor man's barge but now
it's only a slightly poor man's barge
our work here is done
let's head back to the base
unfortunately
we've still got a long way to go on this
now one thing that i was thinking was i
can sort of define
how much area i'm gonna need here by
creating
the staircase that goes down but i
haven't actually figured out
how this connects because hmm maybe i
should do a little test
to see if this slope this steepness
will work or if this will this could
very much
end up like all the way over there i
don't think so
but it might be worth testing just with
like some stone blocks or something
it's not like we're going to run out of
them so if we start here has anyone got
a
ton of gun powder to for sale we got
loads
we got loads of gunpowder is it worth
your life ren has got a bounty
on his head if you bring the box
and your face it's a
deal if you bring it
trading on this server just got really
weird
you bring the box and your face and it's
a done deal
all right he's on his way all right
let's see if we can get this up here
first while we wait for ren we'll uh see
if this actually works this is just a
test to see
if this will work out i have a feeling
it won't look
quite right but we'll see as i suspected
that has fallen quite a lot short
so i think it might have to be
a one block up there
one block staircase all the way down
because this
is uh it's not going to cut it so i mean
it would work if the staircase started
probably somewhere over here but i
don't think that will look quite right
so let's see if i start it right here
where is this going to end up i wonder
if friend knows where i live oh
he's there he's just just watching me
hey dude
oh hi hi hi uh you just caught me from
working on my base
dude yeah very grand
thanks i must say i've been i've been
crying and sweating and tearing over it
you know
it's looking absolutely amazing so you
need yourself some gunpowder
yeah i'm taking tree chopping to the
next level on the server dude
quadruple tnt tree chopper but gonna
need
insane amounts of uh blow blowy up stuff
so actually i can help you because it so
happens i need something that you got
and it's right okay i'm listening oh i'm
looking at it i need i need that face i
need that very sunburned face
um for the kids to elaborate you're
worth 250 points
and i am lagging behind so you sacrifice
uh your your head and i will
give you all the gun powder you need 250
points you don't say ladies get in line
man i'm
i'm valuable on this server that
actually makes you feel pretty good and
if you need some sand for that tnt
there's uh there's a new shop in town
that's selling so you know what i mean
okay nice uh nice plug there
follow me follow me under the under the
sims crystal
if you will please okay is
is this where death is imminent or no no
no we'll go and get we'll go and get the
gunpowder first so you know you know
it's legit um
this is like the inner workings of of
our bases
okay we haven't it doesn't look quite as
uh neat and tidy down here
uh if you bring the box i've got loads
of gunpowder oh that is tasty
that should be enough for enough
actually yeah that should be enough to
blow up the server
yeah all right now you're into the
bargain follow me
so every time we're doing um a minecraft
execution here
i want to come up with a clever way of
doing it we've already done the
guillotine so i'm afraid you
are about to get burned at the stake
okay um
the price we paid for progression on the
hermitcraft server right yeah yeah yeah
so um you might wanna you wanna wanna
ditch all your things
okay uh i'll just stick them here in the
corner they should be all right right
well this is gonna be the first time in
my minecraft career that i've let one of
my friends set me on fire in minecraft
so okay i'm looking for
this okay you ready uh i think so friend
the dog i hereby
sentence you to death on the fire you
get
burn the okay why burn the witch
i've done that thing wrong okay i'm on
two hearts
[Laughter]
worth it and the deal is done thank you
my dude oh thank you man thank you very
much i i feel
slightly violated but uh yeah this
should help me with my log plans so
you know sacrifices have been made for
diamonds
well that was strange if there's any
other hermits out there and you're
listening
um i will trade goodies for
your um life let's go and submit this
corrales also said that all of the
gravel had gone already
which is totally true we might be on to
a
winner here so i actually brought a
bunch of gravel with me to restock
immediately
i'm a little bit worried that i'm gonna
be basically gathering gravel and sand
for the rest of my hermitcraft career
which i don't want to happen so at some
point the price i think is gonna have to
go
up because we're clearly selling out i
mean it's only been two days and i've
already made a lot of diamonds
there we go we've restocked some of it
and we have made a 40 diamond profit
nine of which will go towards our
investment into this we just need a few
more i need these diamonds
for my day-to-day runnings this is
working out wonderfully
oh yeah i came here to submit wren's
head that i just got
so ren 250 points
add this to our score but i'm afraid
that is all we have time for today we
actually have a date
for when this game will end so the end
is near for the point collection
it's been a very very fun game but i am
in it to win it
so hopefully we can still make this work
in our favor i want those diamonds
nom nom nom see you in the next one